《黑镜》
太棒了  来啊
Fuck, yeah! Come on!
∮ 我陷入了爱河 ∮
∮ I'm in love, I'm in love ∮
∮ 我爱上了一台精密机器 ∮
∮ I'm in love with a strick machine ∮
∮ 我陷入了爱... ∮
∮ I'm in love... ∮
我没看到他  米娅
I didn't see him, Mia.
该死
Fuck!
该死的
Fucking hell, man.
罗伯  我们得去看看
Rob, we've gotta go and look.
天呐  罗伯
Oh, my gosh, Rob.
没事的  宝贝
It's all right, baby.
天呐
Oh, my God...
- 该死的  - 天呐
- Fucking... - Oh, my God!
该死
Fuck.
罗伯  我们得叫人来
Rob, we've gotta call someone.
不不不  该死的  米娅  动动脑子
No, no, no, no, no, no. Fucking hell, Mia. Think, OK, hey?
我们得动脑子  宝贝
You need to think, baby.
- 我们嗑药了  是吧  - 嗯
- We've been fucking caning it, yeah? - Yeah.
我...
And I...
这要蹲监狱的  我们肯定要蹲监狱的
This is prison, yeah? A fucking instant prison.
天知道我喝了多少酒  现在我撞了人
I've got fuck knows how much drink in me, I fucking hit a guy.
他们会让我进监狱的  是我开的车
Now, they will put me in the cell. I'm the driver, they'll fu...
他们会让我进监狱  我就出不来了
They'll put me in a cell and fucking keep me there.
- 就是这样的  - 我们不能就丢下他
- That's what they'll fucking... - We can't just leave him here.
闭嘴  米娅
Shut the fuck up, Mia!
- 闭嘴  -  那我们就把他丢这儿吗
- Shut... - And just leave him here in the road?!
我得想想  我得想想
I need to fucking think, OK? I need to think.
该死
Fuck!
那边有个湖
OK, there's, there's a lake over there.
后箱里还有睡袋
And there's a sleeping bag in the boot.
你盯住路上
You keep an eye on the road!
- 不  - 你盯住路上
- No. - Keep an eye on the road!
不
No.
No!
- 米娅  - 别
- Mia. - Don't.
米娅  来  跟我一起弄睡袋
Mia, come on. Get the bag with me. Get the bag.
- 不  放开  - 宝贝  来
- No. No, get off. - Baby, come on.
该死
Fuck.
你去拿石头  我来放  好吗
You get the fucking rocks, I'll stack them, OK?
我需要更多石头
I need more fucking rocks.
放成一堆  堆成一堆
Just put a pile, put the fucking pile there.
堆成一堆
Put the pile...
拉上  拉上  拉过头
Close it up. Close it up. Close his head. Close his head.
三
Three...
二
two...
一
one.
《致命鳄鱼》
很荣幸今天能在这么多嘉宾面前
Um, it's an honor to be speaking here today
进行讲话
amongst such impressive company.
我很激动能够分享...
Uh, I'm thrilled to have been shared...
我很激动能受邀
I'm thrilled to have been asked
来分享我对未来的展望
to share my vision of the future, such as it is.
环顾这个世界里的不公  不宽容
Looking around at a world of injustice, intolerance
和巨大的环境挑战
and huge environmental challenges,
让人很难想象光明的未来
it's hard to imagine a bright future,
但我们还是可以的  也必须这么做
but we can and we must.
只有这样  我们才能建造更好的未来
It's the only way that we can build a better tomorrow.
我先讲个好笑的故事
So I'll start with a funny story.
好  我走了
Right. I'm off.
再见
Bye-bye.
- 回见  - 明天见
- See you later on. - See you tomorrow.
好
Ok.
- 今天愉快  - 你也是
- Have a nice day. - You too.
- 再见  妈妈  - 给
- Bye, Mom! - There we go.
好呀  狗狗
Hiya, puppy.
稍等一下
One moment.
来了
Coming!
马上
Just a second!
- 卡迈克尔夫人  - 什么事
- Mrs. Carmichael? - Yes?
我代表领域保险来找您
I'm here on behalf of Realm Insurance.
需要登记你关于事故的记忆
Just need to log your recollections about the accident.
- 我可以进来吗  - 那好
- Am I all right to come in? - Uh, OK then.
她成为了
Someone who has risen to become
同代中最富有创造力的建筑师
one of the most innovative architects of her generation.
不仅是设计建筑  还打造社区
Not just an architect of buildings, but communities.
我介绍得够多了  有请米娅·诺兰
But enough of me telling you about her. Please welcome Mia Nolan.
谢谢  马丁  很荣幸今天能在这么多
Thank you, Martin. Thanks. It's an honor to be speaking here
嘉宾面前进行讲话
amongst such impressive company.
晚上好  欢迎光临栅栏披萨
Good evening, welcome to Fences Pizza.
您的披萨可以取了
Your pizza is ready for collection.
是谁
Hello?
是我
It's me.
- 你的下巴是染病了吗  - 去你的
- Did your chin catch Dutch fur disease? - Yeah, fuck you.
我没说我不喜欢  进来吧
I didn't say I didn't like it. Come in.
有多久了  已经两年了吧
What's it been? It's been like two years now, hasn't it?
三年
Uh, three.
找到我酒店房间来  肯定是要事
Dropping in on my hotel room, it must be important.
- 我们找个地方吃饭吧  - 我...
- Shall we find somewhere to eat? - Yeah, well, I...
我联系你是因为我听说你回来了
I got in touch 'cause I saw that you were in town
为了参加建筑什么的
for what is it, some, some architecture thing?
是个论坛
It's a forum, they call it.
人们花钱来听我讲话
People actually pay to come and listen to me talk.
想想看
Imagine that.
我都快烦死了
Almost does my head in.
你气色不错  是因为健身吗
And you're looking good. Is that the gym?
你看上去
Well, you look...
我看上去像坨屎  米娅  你就不用客气了
I look like dog shit, Mia. I'll save you the bother.
就是屎
Dried-up dog shit.
- 想喝一杯吗  - 我戒了
- Do you want a drink? - I knocked it on the head.
怎么  你完全戒掉了
What, you quit, like fully quit?
九个月三周零两天
Nine months, three weeks, two days.
厉害  这很好
Well done. Well, that's great.
你喝吧
You go ahead.
- 真的  喝吧  - 你确定吗
- Really, go on. - You sure?
- 确定  - 好
- Absolutely. - OK.
那你真不该来这儿见我
You picked a terrible place to come see me 'cause
外面弥漫着啤酒花的味儿
it reeks of hops all the way down the street outside here.
- 你注意到了吗  - 没有
- Did you notice that? - No.
浓浓的啤酒味
It's like a full-on beer smell.
可不利于你戒酒
Can't help your sobriety, that.
但我可能不应该谈酒  是吧
But I probably shouldn't be talking about booze, should I?
罗伯  希望你不是来谈我...
Rob, I hope you're not here to talk about what I...
我就是来谈那个的
It's about that, yeah.
我又在想那晚的事了
I've been thinking about it again, that night.
- 罗伯  - 我无法不去想
- Rob. - I can't not think about it.
我们说好不去想它了
We said that we'd put it out of our minds.
我们不是要试着不谈了吗
Weren't we just gonna try and keep it out?
我做不到  抱歉
I can't. I'm sorry.
已经过去很久了
It was a long time ago.
但在我脑子里  它栩栩如生
Well, in here, it's now.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
为什么偏偏挑今天
Why today? Why is it preying on your mind today?
- 有一篇新闻报道  - 新闻报道
- There's a news story. - A news story?
一篇特稿之类的
Uh, a featured article. Well, whatever you call it.
我帮你打印出来了
I printed it for you.
米娅
Mia?
这就是她  他的妻子
That... That's her. It's his wife.
你不知道那是他妻子
You don't know that's his wife.
底下有张他的照片
There is a photo of him at the bottom.
就是他
It's him.
这个可怜鬼  他们一直没找到他
And the poor cunt, they never found him.
所以她没有再婚
So she never remarried.
她没有搬家
She never fucking moved house.
她就住在原来的地方  等他回家
She stayed where she is in case he came back.
米娅  一直以来  她都在等他
All this time, Mia, she's still waiting for him.
这太不幸了  但我们能做什么
That's dreadful. But what can we do?
我要给她写一封信
I'm gonna write her a letter.
- 不  - 匿名信
- No. - Anonymous.
- 我不会提到你的  - 罗伯  不
- I am not gonna mention you. - Rob, no.
你会搞出一堆事  把那事再翻出来
You'll open up God knows what, you'll just rake it all up.
- 我承受不住了  米娅  - 现在有技术
- I can't live with it, Mia. - There's things they can do.
他们可以追踪到你
'Cause they can trace it back.
他们可以追踪它  找到尸体  找到我们
They can trace it. They'll find the body, they'll find us.
他们不会找到我们的
They won't find us.
是的  他们会的  那时我们就完了
Yes, they will, then we're fucked.
听着  我开始戒酒的时候
Look, when I quit alcohol,
他们叫我去补偿我伤害过的人
they told me to make amends with anyone I've ever hurt.
还有谁比她被我伤得更重呢
Who have I hurt more than her?
你也不应该伤害其他人  那我呢
Also say you're not supposed to hurt anyone else. What about me?
- 那她呢  - 不  不  不
- What about her? - No, no, no.
不
No.
不  操
No! Fuck!
是你的主意  是你的主意
It was your idea. It was your fucking idea!
我明白  我明白  我很抱歉
I know. I know, and I'm sorry.
15年了  我的羞耻  我的罪恶感
Fifteen years, 15 years, the fucking shame, the fucking guilt!
我有了成就  我有我的生活
I've got somewhere. I've got a life.
你不知道  你不明白
You don't know, don't understand.
那不是重点
That's not the point, though.
你不理解
You don't understand.
你没有结婚  我有个儿子  他只有九岁
You're not married. I've got a son. He's nine years old.
你见过他的照片  请你想想他吧
You've seen photos of him. Think of him, please.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我帮你掩盖了
I sat on this for you.
- 我为你掩盖了这事  - 抱歉  我很抱歉
- I fucking sat on this for you! - I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
看着我
Hey, look at me.
- 看着我  - 我下定决心了  就是这样
- Look at me. - I've made up my mind, and that's how it is.
拜托  求你了
Please, please, please.
求你了  罗伯
Please, please, please, Rob.
听着  我明白  我明白
Hey, listen, I understand. I understand.
是吗
Do you?
嗯  来  我们谈一谈
Yeah. Come on, let's talk about this.
不不  我不能留在这里
No, no, I can't stay here.
- 不  不  - 你在做什么  放开我
- No, no, no, no. - What are you doing? Let go!
米娅  我要走了
Mia, I'm fucking leaving.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
米娅  放...米娅  放...手
Mia, let the... Mia, let the fuck... Let the fuck... go!
操
Fuck...
(事故报告  索赔人信息)
"老家伙"
Codger.
它的名字是"老家伙"
That's his name, Codger.
什么
What?
- 你不喜欢它  - 不是的
- Ah, you don't like him. - Oh, it's not that.
给你挑礼物真困难
It's so hard to get presents for you.
不  我喜欢  它...毛茸茸的
No, I like him. He's... fluffy.
没错  阿里会喜欢它的
Exactly. No, Ali's gonna love him.
只是我们有不少事要忙  阿里的情况还有...
It's just we've got a lot going on, what with Ali and...
我把它退回去
I'll take him back.
那个宠物店的人还挺好说话  没事
The pet shop guy was OK. It won't be a problem.
不不不  你说得对  这对阿里有好处
No, no, no, no, you're right. It'll be good for Ali.
把老家伙留下吧
Codger stays.
它是房客老家伙
He's... Codger the lodger.
要换尿布了
Changing time. Uh...
- 生日快乐  - 谢谢
- Happy birthday. - Thanks.
(正在上传)
客房服务
Room service.
好的  谢谢
Lovely, thank you.
(18岁以上  成人视频)
(X坦白)
你好  亲爱的
Hi. Hiya, love.
嗯  不  演讲很顺利
Yeah, it was... No, the speech went great.
我早上回去
Yeah, I'm back in the morning.
我就是累了
I'm just tired, that's all.
是吗  那好啊
Did he? Oh, that's great.
不  别让他接电话
No, don't put him on.
爸爸说你今天彩排很不错
Hey, Dad said you were great in your rehearsal for your play.
你彩排得不错吗  我真为你骄傲
You had a good rehearsal? Yeah, I'm proud of you.
我爱你
I love you.
(诺兰  适合所有人的廉价房屋)
(是否重播)
住了一晚
So that's one night.
你点了客房服务还有9.99镑的付费电影
You had room service and a £9.99 charge for the movie.
电影
For a movie?
你昨晚没有看一部电影吗
You... you watched a film last night, no?
对  我昨晚在房里  是的
Yeah. I was in last night, yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
Thank you.
(21号前哨站)
我是领域保险的  是为那辆披萨车事故来的
I'm from Realm Insurance, about the pizza van accident.
请进
Oh, come in.
这最多能支付你四个月的费用
I mean, it'll cover you for up to four months,
但这也是一大笔索赔了
but that is quite a substantial claim.
我本来下周要跟着交响乐团去巡回演出
Well, I was heading off on tour with the Philharmonic next week.
欧洲  中东  澳大利亚
Europe, Middle East, Australia.
现在去不了了
Not now.
你肯定也知道  这样一大笔钱
As I'm sure you appreciate, with a payout of this size,
- 我们必须得调查这个事故  - 当然
- we will need to investigate the accident. - Yeah, of course.
那整条街
Now, that stretch of the street
都有监控摄像  不过被破坏了
has a security camera, vandalized,
我猜是孩子玩彩弹时弄坏的
by some kids, I'm guessing, paintballed right in the wrong place.
但是
But the, um...
送餐车上肯定有摄像头吧
delivery van thing must've had a camera.
- 不好使  - 不是吧
- Not working. - Oh, for God's sake.
不  那其实对你的索赔是件好事
No, that's actually good for your claim.
栅栏披萨是个大公司
Fences Pizza's a big company.
他们一直大肆宣传
They're been press claiming
他们的无人驾驶车队记录良好
their driverless fleet has a good record.
有故障的摄像头  可以证明他们工作的疏忽
The malfunctioning camera, that's a step toward negligence.
如果我们能证明是他们的全责  你还可以考虑
So if we can prove full liability, you could also consider
在我们的法律部帮助下提起大额民事诉讼
filing a substantial civil case under our litigation wing?
可以索赔很多钱
Could be a lot of money.
好吧  我没意见
Yeah, OK, I'm sold.
好的
Great.
现在  我要给你
Now, I'll just hook you up
连上这个回忆器
to the recaller here.
这就是那种记忆挖取器吗
It's one of those memory dredgers?
我们更喜欢叫取证器
We prefer "corroborators."
不是警察的工具吗
Police things, aren't they?
去年开始不再仅限于他们了
Not since last year.
现在我们也有了
We all have them now.
好了
Right.
- 可以吗  - 好的
- May I? - Yeah.
我感觉自己像个样本
I feel like a specimen.
这个东西会读取忆痕
So, this accesses engrams,
也就是你对事件的记忆
your memories of what happened.
你的记忆是主观的
Now, they're subjective.
也许不完全准确  而且往往有强烈情绪
They may not be totally accurate, and they're often emotional,
但是通过收集包括你
but by collecting a range of
和其他目击者在内的一系列记忆
recollections from yourself and any witnesses,
我们就能为构建完整案件经过提供帮助
we can help build a corroborative picture of the whole.
我什么都不记得  一片空白
I don't remember anything. It's a total blank.
我或许能提供点帮助
Oh, I've got something that might help.
怎么  喝醉酒就行吗
What, getting drunk?
事故发生地离城堡港酿酒厂
The accident happened a few hundred meters
只有几百米
from the Castle Port Brewery.
整片地区都一股酒吧味儿
The whole area smells like a pub.
不用喝  闻一下就行
No sipping, just take a sniff.
气味对记忆有刺激作用  能帮你回忆起
Aroma's a great memory boost, helps anchor you
当时的状况
to where you were.
确实有点印象
Oh... that's familiar.
好  现在把这味道记在心里
OK. Now, hold that smell in your mind,
闭上眼睛  回想那条街道
close your eyes and picture the street.
有结果了
Getting something now.
我去了一家漫画店之类的地方
Yeah. I went to a sort of comic shop...
(21号前哨站)
都是些宅向的东西
Culty stuff. Um...
我记得我出门时开始下雪了
I think it started snowing when I came out.
很大的雪
Heavy snow, um...
有辆车里放着音乐
There was music from a car.
我喜欢这首歌
I like that song.
有个穿黄衣服的女的朝我走来
There was a woman in a yellow coat coming towards me.
她的脸记得很清楚
Good recall on her face.
她涂的口红特别怪  特别扎眼
She had this weird lipstick on. It stood out.
而且她很漂亮
And she's pretty.
没错  的确很漂亮
Um, yeah, yeah, and that, too.
你的反应越情绪化
Well, the more emotional your response,
你的记忆就越生动
the more vivid your memory of it is.
所以有音乐和一个女孩
So there was the music and a girl,
然后发生了什么
and then what happened?
然后我就过路
Well, I went to cross the road,
心里其实也没想什么
wasn't really thinking about anything,
然后
and, uh...
然后事情就发生了
And that's just when it just goes. Um...
没事  你提供的已经很有用了
That's OK. What you've given me is already useful.
真的
Really?
让我发现了下一个目标  黄衣女郎
Well, I've got someone to look for, Little Miss Yellow Coat.
流浪汉终于回家了
Ah, the wanderer returns.
- 是啊  - 你知道怎么修这个吗
- Yeah. - You don't know how to fix this, do you?
知道  我待会儿看看
Um, yeah, I'll have a look at it later.
- 好啊  妈妈  - 好啊  你
- Hi, Mom. - Hi, you.
今晚就要上台了
Tonight's the big night.
- ∮ 我们想做什么就能做什么 ∮ - 老爸
- ∮ We coulda been anything that we wanted to be... ∮ - Dad!
他们学校的音乐剧  《龙蛇小霸王》
School musical, Bugsy Malone.
你没事吧
You all right?
没事
Yeah. Yeah.
他们弄了一套音响系统来放配乐
They've got this, um, sound system for the backing tracks
但他们不会用  我就说我帮他们
that they can't work out and I said I'd help them out.
所以我得在学校待一整天
So... I'm gonna be there all day.
你不会孤单死吧
You're gonna die of loneliness here, are you?
才不会
Yeah, I'll be fine.
晚点见  7:30
Well, we'll see you later, 7:30.
别忘了
Don't forget.
不会的
I won't.
- 回头见  - 再见
- See ya. - See you later.
再见
Bye.
(发现匹配)
昨天才发生的事  你真高效
It was only yesterday. You're efficient.
事件越近  记忆就越清晰
The fresher the memory, the stronger it is,
越清晰  就越有利于案子
and the stronger the memory, the stronger the case.
你来闻一下这个
I'll also just get you to take a sniff of this.
别人看到会怎么想啊
God knows what they think we're doing in here.
闭上眼睛  我会放段音乐
If you close your eyes, I'm also gonna play a piece of music.
对  当时确实在放这首歌
God, yeah, yeah, that, that was on.
真奇怪
How weird.
记住这些东西  想象一下你看到的画面
Hold those things in your mind and picture what you saw.
我当时在斯坦霍普路  宾馆附近
I was on Stanhope Road, near the hotel place,
浏览橱窗里的东西  随便看看
looking at flats and stuff, you know, window shopping.
我看到一个男的迎面走来
I saw this guy walking towards me.
我记得当时还在想他长得挺不错
I remember thinking he looked sort of sweet.
音乐是停在路边的一辆车里放的
The music was coming from the car, which pulled off.
那个时候送餐车刚好经过
Actually that was when the delivery thing drove past.
栅栏披萨  车速多少
Fences Pizza? What sort of speed was it going?
你是问它超速了吗
You mean, was it going too fast?
- 重点放在那辆车上  - 也许吧
- Try and focus on the vehicle. - Maybe.
(速度检测)
(无法检测)
我不知道  我不确定
I don't know. I couldn't really say.
撞击厉害吗
What about the impact itself?
撞上的那一刻我没看到  之后我才看到的
Well, I didn't really see it. I just saw the aftermath, really.
这之前你还看到了一道亮光
A moment earlier you saw a bright light?
对  就像相机的闪光灯
Yeah. Like a camera flash just before.
就在牙医诊所外
Just outside the dentist place.
(坎布鲁克口腔护理)
这里都是隔音窗吧
And I'm assuming your window glazing's soundproof.
对  偶尔有人会尖叫
Yes, we get the odd screamer.
那我就不给你放音乐了
I won't bother with the music then.
记忆画面会有点尴尬
Look, to be honest, the memory's a bit embarrassing...
别担心  我什么都见识过
Don't worry, I've seen it all.
必须得用那玩意吗
Do you have to use that thing?
你的记忆是绝对保密不会公开的
Look, your memories will be sealed and private.
除非画面显示你伤害了自己或他人
Unless they indicate you're harming yourself or another person.
那来吧
Go on then.
我当时有个病人
I'd had a patient.
我看到了
So I see.
她应该是6点左右离开的
She left around six, I think.
我留下来整理
I stayed to clear up.
你在窗外看到什么了吗
You saw something from the window?
宾馆窗户里有个男的
There was a guy in the hotel window.
怎么说呢
Well, what can I say?
秀色可餐
He was picturesque.
你拍照了吗
Did you take a photo?
我想拍
Well, I tried to.
但忘记关闪光灯了  所以什么也没拍到
I left the flash on by mistake, so all I got was the reflection.
- 然后呢  - 我本想再拍一次
- And then? - I was going to take another one.
我看到有个女人直直盯着下面
I saw some woman staring at something.
我往下看  底下一阵骚动
So I looked down, it was just a load of commotion.
有个穿青绿色外套的女人
There was a woman in a sort of lime coat.
其实是黄色
Yellow actually.
- 反正是很艳的颜色  - 记忆会有点主观
- Well, I knew it was vivid. - Well, memories can be subjective.
我们基于群众看到的碎片画面
What we do is build up an overall average,
综合建立起完整的场景
a crowd-sourced picture of reality.
你看到那辆车撞上行人了吗
Did you see the vehicle that hit the pedestrian?
对车速有估计吗
Any sense of its speed?
车祸发生时我并没有看见  抱歉
I didn't see the actual crash, sorry.
好吧
Ok.
那照片你不会说出去吧
You won't tell anyone about the photo?
我不非得写进报告里
Don't need to put that in my report.
我会保密的
It's safe with me.
那应该是304房间
That'd be room 304.
你能告诉我住客是谁吗
Can you tell me who stayed there?
- 你不是警察吗  - 不是  不过
- You're not the police? - No, but...
那你必须申请索要这些信息了
Then you'd have to lodge for an information request for that.
可是流程可能得要一周啊
But that could take up to a week to process.
抱歉  上头对这事要求很严
Sorry, management's an ass about it
自从那个谁出了事  艳照法官
ever since that thing with what's-his-name, the judge of Hot Shots?
总之他被人发现找了男妓
Anyway, he got caught with a rent boy and,
一家小报黑进我们的登记系统搞到了他的名字
a tabloid got his name by hacking our booking system,
他们现在对这个管得很严
and yeah, they're tight as anything about the rule now.
我想找的这个女人倒也没做什么
Oh, the woman I'm after hasn't done anything.
我只是觉得她可能看到了外面发生的事
I just think she might have seen something outside
就在昨晚6:30左右
yesterday evening about 6:30.
我能
Oh, I can...
我能告诉你她并不在户外
I can tell you that she wasn't outside...
而且我也知道她在看什么
and I know what she was looking at.
怎么说
How so?
我不能透露具体的身份
I can't tell you who she is but,
不过她喜欢有趣的电影
um, she's into interesting films.
我们记录了住客在客房内看的电影  而且
We log the inhouse movies that people watch and, um...
她选的片子非常显眼
her choice stood out.
她可真会享受  多谢了
How nice for her. Thanks.
多谢你
Oh, bless you.
披萨车事件查得怎么样了
How's the pizza accident going?
麻烦死了
Hmm. A pain in the ass.
还是不能确定责任
Can't pinpoint liability
大家对那破玩意的车速一人一个说法
cause no one agrees on the speed of the bloody thing
我又找不到任何撞击发生时刻的目击者
and I can't find anyone who actually saw the impact.
暂时还没
Well, not yet.
除了这位不知道是谁的模糊脸小姐
Except maybe smudge face here, whoever she is.
查到了
Oh, bingo.
米娅·诺兰
Mia Nolan.
如果你肯开口  你就是关键证人了
You might be the one, if you'll talk.
她为什么会不开口
What, if she'll talk?
她当时正在酒店房间里做羞羞的事情
She was doing something embarrassing in the hotel room,
在看黄片
watching a porn film.
她恐怕不会同意我在她的记忆里摸索
She might not want me poking around in her head.
她家就在城外50英里
She's, like, 50 miles out of town.
我能现在就去她家吗
Do you mind if I head there now?
现在有点晚了
It's a bit late.
如果我能一天之内结案  我就能领双份奖金
Oh, if I sew this up in 24 hours, I get two times bonus.
好吧
Well...
去吧  去吧
Go. Go.
∮ 我知道我绝不会放开你 ∮
∮ I know I won't ever let you go ∮
∮ 离开你哪怕一刻  我都无法忍受 ∮
∮ Oh, it's more than I could ever stand ∮
∮ 可是对于任何 ∮
∮ Oh, but anyone ∮
你好  我是领域保险的沙奇亚
Hi, I'm Shazia. I'm from Realm Insurance.
我已经买保险了  多谢
I've already got insurance, thanks.
我不是来推销的
I'm not selling anything.
我是来调查一件你可能目击的案件
I'm following up on an incident you might've seen,
一起车祸
a road accident.
我不知道什么车祸
I don't know anything about an accident.
事情就在昨天
This was only yesterday.
- 什么车祸  - 在斯坦霍普路
- An accident? - On Stanhope Road.
梅地纳广场酒店外有个路人被送货车撞了
Medina Plaza Hotel, a pedestrian was hit by a delivery vehicle,
无人驾驶的栅栏披萨送餐车
Fences Pizza, driverless.
对了  抱歉  我还真看见了
Right, yeah. I'm sorry, actually I did.
你刚提的时候
When you first mentioned it,
我没想到  但我确实看到了
I just didn't think of it, but um... yeah, I did.
你目击了事发经过
So you saw what happened?
没错  当时有个男人在过马路
Uh, yeah, there was a guy crossing the street
有辆小货车撞到了他  车速挺快
and this little van thing sort of just clipped him, it was quick.
介意我问你一些相关问题吗
Do you mind if I ask you a few questions about it?
不用太久
It won't take long.
抱歉  我很忙  我有...
I'm sorry, I'm really busy. I've got...
我不想说得太严重
I don't wanna sound heavy
但去年开始这就是法律要求了
but it's a legal requirement since last year.
这是法律要求吗
It's a legal requirement?
如果你目击了事故的话
Well, if you've witnessed an incident, yes.
如果人们拒绝我就得通知警方
I have to notify the police when people refuse,
一旦警方卷入  事情就会很拖拉
and when they get involved, it just drags everything out, so...
- 进来吧  - 谢谢
- Come in. - Thank you.
那边请
Yeah, just that way.
好
Ok.
- 那是干吗的  - 回忆器吗
- What does that do? - The recaller?
帮我记录事发经过
Just helps me get a record of what happened.
我帮你连上
May I?
我可以直接告诉你情况  我记得
Well, I can just tell you what happened. I can remember.
货车撞了那个人  那人摔倒了
The van hit the guy, and he fell over,
然后有人来帮忙
and then people came to help.
当时车速有多快  那辆送餐车
How fast was it going though, the delivery vehicle?
我只需要了解那个
See, I just need a sense of that.
有时很难描述记忆里的景象
It's sometimes hard to articulate what your mind's eye's seen,
但捕捉你的所见所感很有帮助
but capturing your impression of what you saw is really useful.
- 但我...  - 我只关心这件事
- OK, but I've got... - And that's all I'm interested in.
你可以看这些条款
You can read the terms here if you like.
法规都写明白了
All the legal stuff is in there.
我不关心你私下里
Look, I don't care what you might've been doing
在酒店房间做了什么
in the hotel room in your own time.
我不会问私人问题  不会的
I'm not gonna ask you anything about that. Won't go there.
- 好吧  - 私事就是私事
- OK. - Private stuff is private stuff.
- 只问车祸的事  - 只问车祸
- So it's just the accident? - Just that.
得花点时间看啊
It's a bit of a long read, isn't it?
- 你想喝茶还是咖啡  - 咖啡最好了
- Do you want a tea or a coffee? - Oh, a coffee would be great.
- 行  浓缩咖啡  - 好
- Yeah, OK. Espresso? - Perfect.
我失陪小解一下
Do you mind if I just go and have a pee
感觉我得坐好一会儿
if I'm gonna be sat down a while?
- 没问题  - 好
- Yeah, sure. - OK.
我吃了酒店食物  叫了客房服务
I ate hotel food, I had room service.
我吃了客房服务的食物
I ate room service.
我一个人在酒店房间里
I was in the hotel room on my own.
看成人片
Watched porn.
看到了车祸
Saw the accident.
集中注意力
Come on, focus.
我一个人
I was on my own.
给你
There you go.
闻一下
Take a sniff.
- 干什么  - 有助于你回忆
- What's that for? - It'll just help your recall.
好了
That's it.
这首歌也能帮你回忆
The music will help jog your memory, too.
闭上双眼
OK, close your eyes.
想想你在酒店房间里
OK, let's start with you in your hotel room.
我当时在房间  叫了客房服务
So I was in my room and I ordered room service.
我只需要车祸的场景
All I need is the accident.
尽量去回忆车祸前的场景
Try to picture the moments leading up to the impact.
我的羞耻  我的罪恶感
The fucking shame, the fucking guilt...
不
No.
No!
- 我帮你  - 从我身上下去
- I sat on this... - Get the fuck off me fucking...
很好
Well, that's... great.
关于车的信息都有了  我这就走了
Got what I needed on the van, so, I'll be off.
好的
Ok.
行了
That's it.
- 你需要的信息都有了吗  - 是的
- So you've got everything you needed? - Yeah.
不用很长  就只需要车速的信息
Doesn't take that long, it's just a simple thing with the speed so...
- 好的  - 嗯
- Right. - Yeah. Yeah.
抱歉不能再多留你  这一天太累了
Sorry about being short, it's been a long day.
- 没事  - 还有很多工作
- No, it's fine. - Got a lot of work on. Did you...
- 你确定想要的信息都有了吗  - 都有了
- So you've got everything you needed? - Yeah, yeah, got it all.
- 没事  非常感谢  - 听起来可能有点蠢
- Don't worry, thank you so much. - I know this sounds silly,
但我有时会想一些疯狂的事情
but, you know, sometimes I just think mad things,
并不能说明什么
and it doesn't mean anything,
你懂我意思吗  有时有些奇怪的想法
do you know what I mean? When you have strange thoughts.
没事的  我想要的都有了  谢谢
No, it's fine, like I said. I got what I needed, so thank you.
但你明白我的意思吗
Yeah, but do you know what I mean?
我不是  只是脑袋里的胡思乱想
It's not like... it's just my head.
快啊
Come on!
不
No.
不  不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no! No!
不
No!
抱歉
I'm sorry,
我搞砸了  我慌了
I fucked up, and I panicked.
你的头疼吗
Does your head hurt?
好吧
Ok.
我该拿你怎么办呢
What am I gonna do with you?
我又不能让你走
I mean, I can't let you go.
你会告诉别人的  对吧
You're gonna tell someone, aren't you?
我知道  但就算你说你不会
I know, but even if you say you won't,
但你的回忆都被记录下来了
your recollections are all recorded.
- 我不会说的  - 没记录吗
- I won't. - They're not?
没有
No.
如果我把那个拿下来  你能保证不叫吗
If I take that off your mouth, will you promise not to scream?
能保证吗
Do you promise?
别担心报告的事  我会删除
Forget the report. I'll delete...
我会删除的  不会流出去
I'll delete it, it won't go anywhere.
我不知道  我试着删除  但不会弄
I don't know. I tried to delete it, and I couldn't figure it out.
我不会告诉任何人任何事的  我保证
I won't say anything to anyone, I promise.
我会忘记所有事情
I'll forget the whole thing.
没人会知道  我什么都不会说
No one will know. I won't say anything.
我也想相信你
I wish I believed you.
我是说真的  我见过很多事
I mean it. I mean it. I've seen things.
我在回忆器上见过很多事
I've seen things on the recaller.
秘密  私人隐私  我从来没说出去过
Secrets, personal things, I've never spilled any of it.
我也不允许说  这是法律规定
I'm not allowed to, it's the law.
这就像忏悔  天主教忏悔
It's like confession, it's like Catholic confession.
说出去是不合法的
It'll be illegal for me to say anything.
就算我想说也是完全不合法的
Totally illegal, even if I wanted to!
你说的是假话吧
None of that's true, is it?
- 真的  我发誓  - 不是真的
- It is, I swear. - It's not.
是真的
It is.
你有告诉过别人你今天要来这儿吗
Did you tell anyone that you were coming here today?
没有
No.
- 你在说谎  - 我没有  我发誓
- You're lying. - I'm not. I swear I'm not lying.
真的  我发誓
No, I swear.
我发誓  不
I swear. No!
不
No!
你今天来之前做了什么
What did you do before you came here today?
*可是对于任何*
*Oh, but anyone*
- *知道爱情为何物的人*  - 我喜欢这首歌
- *Who knows what love is...* - I like that song.
*都能理解*
*Will understand*
你和谁说过话
Who did you speak to?
查到了
Bingo.
米娅·诺兰  如果你肯开口
Mia Nolan, if she'll talk.
- 她为什么会不开口  - 不
- If she'll talk? - No!
不
No.
- 那是你丈夫吗  - 不
- Is that your husband? - No!
不
No!
我真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
不
No!
能请你闭上眼睛吗
Will you please close your eyes for me?
(地址簿)
(家庭住址)
大家都穿好服装了
Everyone's in their costumes already.
拜托你一定要准时来
Yeah, please, make sure you're on time.
- 我知道  亲爱的  - 你在很远的地方吗
- Yeah, I know, love. - Are you far off?
- 别忘了7:30开始  - 我7:30一定到
- Remember it starts at 7:30. - I'm gonna make it, 7:30.
- 7:30  - 好
- 7:30. - Yeah.
- 那好  - 在外面碰面
- All right. - I'll see you outside.
- 待会儿见  亲爱的  - 好
- See you in a bit, sweetheart. - OK.
- 这么卡点啊  - 工作上的事太多
- Cutting it a bit fine. - Yeah, it was just work stuff.
我的天  你喝了一整座酒庄吗
Jesus, what'd you eat, a vineyard?
不是  我设计完就喝了一杯酒
No, I just finished the design so had a glass of wine.
- 一杯才怪  - 咱们进去行吗
- Fuck off, a glass. - Let's just go in, all right?
好吧
All right, fine.
*我们想做什么*
*We coulda been anything*
*就能做什么*
*That we wanted to be*
*现在想改变还不晚*
*And it's not too late to change*
*我已经决定要考虑考虑*
*It's been decided To give it some thought*
*也许你也同意我该想想了*
*Maybe you'll agree we really ought*
*二  三  四*
*Two, three, four!*
*我们想做什么就能做什么*
*We coulda been anything that we wanted to be*
*决定权在我们手里*
*Yes, that decision was ours*
*事实就是我们不团结就会变弱*
*It's been decided we're weaker divided*
*让我们的友谊提供双倍力量吧*
*Let friendship double up our powers*
刚刚确认发生一起双尸案
Yeah, just confirming double homicide.
一名成年男性和一名男婴
One adult male and one male infant.
我已经到现场了
Yeah, I'm at the scene now.
谁会连婴儿都杀呢
Who kills a baby?
我不知道
I don't know.
也许凶手是害怕留下目击证人
Probably someone worried about leaving a witness.
楼上是血浴  楼下又杀婴
Bloodbath upstairs and this downstairs.
可是他看不见啊
But he couldn't see.
这小可怜是先天失明
Poor fucker was born blind apparently.
所以我得说我完全不知道凶手是谁
So I have to say, I have absolutely no idea who I'm looking for.
所以还好他们不会问我
So it's a good job they're not asking me.
来吧  咱们走吧
Come on, let's clear out of here.
让回忆小队接手吧
Let's let the recall team do their job.
走吧
Come on.
来吧
Here we go.
*付出一点爱  你就会有回报*
*You give a little love and it all comes back to you*
*大家都会记住你*
*You know You're gonna be remembered*
*记住你说的话  做的事*
*For the things that you say and do*
唱得好
Well done!
请大家为我们的校合唱队鼓掌吧
Put your hands together for this year's fantastic school choir.
今晚真是太精彩了  多谢各位前来
What a lovely evening. Thank you so much for coming.
请大家为亨利老师鼓掌
Put your hands together for Mrs. Henry...
太棒了
Bravo!